562-600-0163

dr.jianfeng.wu@gmail.com

Winlock Road, Torrance, CA 90505

Summary

Versatile iOS Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience designing, developing, and managing complex iOS Applications and internal frameworks.

Expert-level Backend Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience who will provide optimum project engineering design, infrastructure construction monitoring and inspection.

Software Architect who has leaded a team to build proprietary enterprise software products and has optimum excitement in using various technologies to design, develop, and attentively deploy real enterprise class software.

Experience

INDEPENDENT DEVELOPER – 2018.10-CURRENT

Designed and developed 10+ iOS applications in e-learning & Internet Of Things area.

Created custom components for internal framework.

CYBEYE INC, TORRANCE, CA - - 2015.7-2018.9

Created an iOS framework to support live-streaming and social network.

Constructed an auto-test and continuous integration platform.

SHANGHAI STOCK EXCHANGE, SHANGHAI, CHINA – 2010.9-2014.6

Leaded team supporting the continuous development and optimization of the trading system.

SHANGHAI STOCK EXCHANGE, SHANGHAI, CHINA - 2000.12-2010.9

Leaded team developing a mission critical system backend to support more than 100 Million users. It means that I have a comprehensive understanding of the architect design for complex business systems, and related experience make me know how to control quality and progress in the full lifecycle of complex software development projects.

Education

Tsinghua University – Ph.D

Skills

Objective-C, Swift for iOS application and library design.

Python for backend server and tools design.

Java for backend server design and Android application design.

Javascript for Progressive Web Application design.

SQL for database design.

Amazon Web Services ecosystem, include API Gateway, IOT, Lambda, RDS, S3, SNS etc.

Git, Svn for Source Code Management.

C, C++ for library and foundation design, include FFmpeg, WebRTC, MQTT, RTMP etc.